<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Rahul&#39;s Presence On Internet</title>
    <link>https://rahulmysore23.github.io/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Rahul&#39;s Presence On Internet</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 01:23:26 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rahulmysore23.github.io/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Startup Interview and Defunct Process</title>
      <link>https://rahulmysore23.github.io/blogs/startup-interview-and-defunct-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 01:23:26 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rahulmysore23.github.io/blogs/startup-interview-and-defunct-process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alright, folks, gather &amp;lsquo;round. Let me tell you the story of my first interview with a blockchain company (which shall remain nameless, because, well, NDAs are a thing). It was Round 1, and the focus was on OS/System Programming. The interview was scheduled for 1 hour and 30 minutes, and I was told to have a Linux environment ready. Sounds simple enough, right? Wrong. This is where the adventure begins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a TUI for Managing Systemd Services: A Fun Side Project</title>
      <link>https://rahulmysore23.github.io/blogs/sysdmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 01:06:28 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rahulmysore23.github.io/blogs/sysdmon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I found myself constantly juggling multiple custom services at work. These services were binaries written in Go, designed for data observability purposes. While they were efficient at their job, managing them was a bit of a hassle. I often had to check their status, restart them, or stop them entirely using the &lt;code&gt;systemctl&lt;/code&gt; command. Typing &lt;code&gt;systemctl status &amp;lt;service&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; over and over again started to feel tedious. Sure, I could have created aliases, but I wanted something more interactive—a &lt;strong&gt;TUI (Terminal User Interface)&lt;/strong&gt; that would make the process smoother and more enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Linux Journey: From Ubuntu to Hyprland, Vim to Tiling Window Managers, and Everything In Between</title>
      <link>https://rahulmysore23.github.io/blogs/linuxjourney/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 16:12:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rahulmysore23.github.io/blogs/linuxjourney/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever fallen down the rabbit hole of Linux, you know how addictive it can be. For me, it all started back in 2016. I was a curious kid with a laptop that barely ran Windows, and I stumbled upon Ubuntu. Little did I know, that first installation would spark a lifelong passion for tinkering, customizing, and optimizing my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-beginning-ubuntu-and-the-linux-curiosity&#34;&gt;The Beginning: Ubuntu and the Linux Curiosity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started with Ubuntu—like most people do. It was simple, user-friendly, and felt like a breath of fresh air compared to Windows. But soon, I wanted more. I tried Pop!_OS for its sleek design and gaming optimizations, Linux Mint for its familiarity, Fedora for its cutting-edge features, and even Garuda Linux because, let’s be honest, it looked &lt;em&gt;cool&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HackMidwest 2024: How We Built a USDA Chatbot in 24 Hours (and Won!)</title>
      <link>https://rahulmysore23.github.io/blogs/hackmidwest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 13:42:32 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rahulmysore23.github.io/blogs/hackmidwest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When my friend and I signed up for &lt;strong&gt;HackMidwest 2024&lt;/strong&gt;, we had no idea what we were going to build. Zero. Zilch. Nada. We showed up with our laptops, a vague sense of excitement, and a whole lot of caffeine. The hackathon kicked off with some awesome workshops—Red Hat OpenShift, AWS, Pinata, and more. We attended as many as we could, soaking up knowledge and trying to figure out what we could possibly create in 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Presence on the Internet</title>
      <link>https://rahulmysore23.github.io/blogs/first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 11:28:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rahulmysore23.github.io/blogs/first_post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in the early days of my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree, a friend of mine started a technical blog called &lt;a href=&#34;http://thecodenote.com&#34;&gt;The Code Note&lt;/a&gt;. I thought it was the coolest thing ever. Inspired, I decided to start my own blog. I spent days brainstorming a name (which, honestly, I can’t even remember now) and finally launched it. It was your typical &amp;ldquo;how to solve LeetCode problems&amp;rdquo; blog. Yeah, I know—there are already millions of those out there. But hey, it got me started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
